Cameron Bentley

cjbentle@edu.uwaterloo.ca | 587-703-6830

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO

BASC IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING Expected 2022 | Waterloo, ON

SKILLS

CAD/TECHNICAL DRAFTING

CAD & Markup Software SolidWorks • AutoCAD • Fusion 360 • BlueBeam Revu

Competencies GD&T • P&IDs • DFM

PROGRAMMING

Experienced C++ • VBA • Bash • HTML

Fundamental Knowledge
Python • JavaScript • CSS • Git
Versioning

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATION

Operating Systems Linux • Windows Server

Software

MySQL • Docker • Hyper-V • apache • nginx • WordPress

Office Software

Word • Excel (VBA, Power Pivot, Power Query) • PowerPoint • LaTeX • Photoshop

COURSEWORK

Electrical Circuits & Instrumentation Electromechanical Devices & Power Processing

Structure & Properties of Materials Control of Properties of Materials Mechanics of Deformable Solids

ADDITIONAL INFO

Certifications & EndorsementsDriver's Licence • H₂S Alive • WHMIS

Citizenship

Canadian & EU Citizenship (UK)

Interests

Automotive • Aerospace • Computers • Robotics

Links

Website: bentley.sh LinkedIn: cameron-bentley

GitHub: cjbentley

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

I am a highly motivated Mechanical Engineering student with strong administration and design skills and a strong interest in the automotive industry. I am ambitious to develop new skills through challenging work placements, as well as to experience new industries and locations. I am capable of working in fast-paced environments as both a leader and a member.

WORK EXPERIENCE

AECON GROUP, INC. | INTERN PROJECT COORDINATOR

January 2019 - April 2019 | Calgary, AB

- Project coordinator for platform installation on Enbridge T-South compressor station.
- Managed requisitions, labour & material tracking, and equipment acquisition.
- Assisted with subcontract disputes, KPI reports, and cost control.

NOUVLR GROUP | ENGINEERING INTERN

September 2018 - December 2018 | Montréal, QC

• Design management intern during early construction phase of the Réseau express métropolitain LRT network in Montréal.

AECON GROUP, INC. | Engineering Intern (2 terms)

May 2017 - Aug. 2017 & Jan. 2018 - Apr. 2018 | Fort St. John, BC & Calgary, AB

- On-site intern during a gas cogeneration facility turnaround operation, and office intern during pre-build phase of CNRL's Kirby North metering station.
- Assisted with project controls, planning, scheduling, QC, and reporting.
- Developed red line corrections and P&ID's for in-field revisions to IFC drawings, and reviewed drawings, models, and PFDs to ensure accuracy prior to issuance.
- Analysed productivity and costs to improve cost control & efficiency.
- Created Site-Specific Safety Plan, Emergency Response Procedure and other critical safety & regulatory documentation.
- Developed procurement contracts and cost comparisons between vendors.
- Processed procurement information with SAP and managed document control.
- Collaborated in development of construction schedule using Primavera P6.
- Automated reporting, document control, and other office processes with Power Pivot, VBA, and Bluebeam.

PROJECTS

WATSAT SATELLITE DESIGN TEAM | STRUCTURES SUBSYSTEM LEAD September 2016 - August 2018 | Waterloo, ON

- Designed components for CubeSat satellite structural redesign.
- Integrated attitude control hardware and communications antennas into the satellite frame.
- Documented and simulated structural design properties for presentation at the Canadian Satellite Design Challenge's CDR (Critical Design Review).
- Developed understanding of DFM and designing to specification (maximizing resistance to stress while minimizing weight and cost to manufacture).

AIM ENGINEERING CHALLENGE | 1ST PLACE GROUP LEADER

January 2016 - May 2016 | Calgary, AB

- Developed & tested a new prototype and presented this prototype to the competition host.
- Group placed first; company integrated suggested changes into new pod design.